I'm here today to talk about a disturbing question,
أنا هنا لأتكلم عن سؤال مزعج
which has an equally disturbing answer.
وله اجابة تتساوى له بالازعاج.
My topic is the secrets of domestic violence,
موضوعي هو أسرار العنف الأسري،
and the question I'm going to tackle
والسؤال الذي سأعالجه
is the one question everyone always asks:
هو السؤال الذي يسأله الجميع دائماً:
Why does she stay?
لماذا تبقى؟
Why would anyone stay with a man who beats her?
لماذا تبقى أي واحدة مع رجل يضربها؟
I'm not a psychiatrist, a social worker
أنا لست اخصائية نفسية ، عاملة اجتماعية
or an expert in domestic violence.
أو خبيرة في العنف الأسري.
I'm just one woman with a story to tell.
أنا فقط أمرأة لديها قصة لتحكيها.
I was 22. I had just graduated from Harvard College.
كنت بال22، كنت قد تخرجت للتو من كلية هارفارد.
I had moved to New York City for my first job
و كنت قد انتقلت إلى مدينة نيويورك لأبدأ عملي الأول.
as a writer and editor at Seventeen magazine.
ككاتبة ومحررة في مجلة "سفنتين"
I had my first apartment,
حصلت على شقتي الأولى،
my first little green American Express card,
بطاقتي الأولى الصغيرة الخضراء "امريكان اكسبريس"،
and I had a very big secret.
وكان لدي سر كبير.
My secret was that I had this gun
سري كان أن لدي هذا المسدس
loaded with hollow-point bullets pointed at my head
المحشو بطلقات مجوفة مصوب على رأسي
by the man who I thought was my soulmate,
من قبل الرجل الذي كنت أعتقده توأم روحي،
many, many times.
عدة ، عدة مرات.
The man who I loved more than anybody on Earth
الرجل الذي أحبتته أكثر من أي شخص على الأرض
held a gun to my head and threatened to kill me
حمل سلاحا عند رأسي وهدد بقتلي
more times than I can even remember.
أكثر من المرات التي أستطيع تذكرها.
I'm here to tell you the story of crazy love,
أنا هنا لأحكي لكم قصة حب مجنون.
a psychological trap disguised as love,
فخ نفسي متمثل بصورة الحب،
one that millions of women and even a few men
ملايين النساء وبعض الرجال
fall into every year.
يقعون فيه كل سنة.
It may even be your story.
من الممكن أن تكون أيضا قصتك.
I don't look like a typical domestic violence survivor.
أنا لا أشبه الصورة النمطية لناجية من العنف الأسري.
I have a B.A. in English from Harvard College,
لدي بكالوريوس في اللغة الانجليزية من كلية هارفارد.
an MBA in marketing from Wharton Business School.
ماجستير في ادارة الاعمال في مجال التسويق من كلية "وارتون" للأعمال
I've spent most of my career working for Fortune 500 companies
قضيت معظم مهنتي أعمل لدي شركات من أفضل 500 شركة أمريكية
including Johnson &amp; Johnson, Leo Burnett and The Washington Post.
تتضمن "جونسون اند جونسون" ، "ليو برينت" و "الواشنطون بوست"
I've been married for almost 20 years to my second husband
أنا متزوجة لتقريبا 20 سنة من زوجي الثاني
and we have three kids together.
ولدينا ثلاثة أطفال سويا.
My dog is a black lab, and I drive a Honda Odyssey minivan.
كلبي لابرودر أسود وأقود حافلة صغيرة "هوندا اوديسي"
(Laughter)
(ضحكة)
So my first message for you is that domestic violence
فرسالتي الأولى لكم هي أن العنف الأسري
happens to everyone --
يحصل للجميع
all races, all religions, all income and education levels.
كل الأعراق، كل الأديان، كل الطبقات الاجتماعية والتعليمية
It's everywhere.
موجود في كل مكان.
And my second message is that everyone thinks
ورسالتي الثانية أن الكل يفكر
domestic violence happens to women,
أن العنف الأسري يحدث للنساء،
that it's a women's issue.
أنه شأن نسائي.
Not exactly.
ليس تماماً.
Over 85 percent of abusers are men, and domestic abuse
أكثر من 85% من المعتدين رجال والعنف الأسري
happens only in intimate, interdependent, long-term relationships,
يحدث فقط في العلاقات الحميمية المترابطة طويلة المدى،
in other words, in families,
بكلام أخر، في العائلات
the last place we would want or expect to find violence,
هو آخر مكان نتوقع و نريد أن نجد فيه العنف،
which is one reason domestic abuse is so confusing.
لهذا السبب العنف الأسري محير جداً.
I would have told you myself that I was the last person on Earth
كنت أقول لنفسي أنا آخر انسانة على وجه الأرض
who would stay with a man who beats me,
اللتي يمكن أن تبقى مع رجل يضربها.
but in fact I was a very typical victim because of my age.
لكن بالواقع كنت ضحية نمطية بسبب عمري.
I was 22, and in the United States,
كنت بعمر 22 ، وفي الولايات المتحدة
women ages 16 to 24 are three times as likely
النساء في الولايات المتحدة بين عمر 16 وال 22 أكثر عرضة بتلاث مرات
to be domestic violence victims
أن يكونوا ضحايا عنف أسري
as women of other ages,
من النساء بأعمار أخرى،
and over 500 women and girls this age
وأكثر من 500 امرأة وفتاة في هذا العمر
are killed every year by abusive partners,
يقتلن سنويا بسبب شركاء مسيئين
boyfriends, and husbands in the United States.
وأحباء وأزواج في الولايات المتحدة.
I was also a very typical victim because I knew nothing
وكنت أيضاٌ ضحية نمطية لأنني لم أكن أعلم شيئاً
about domestic violence, its warning signs or its patterns.
عن العنف الأسري، علاماته التحذيرية أو أنماطه.
I met Conor on a cold, rainy January night.
قابلت "كونر" في يوم بارد ،ممطر من ليالي يناير.
He sat next to me on the New York City subway,
جلس بجانبي في مترو مدينة نيويورك،
and he started chatting me up.
وبدأ بالتحدث معي.
He told me two things.
قال لي شيئين.
One was that he, too, had just graduated from an Ivy League school,
شيء أنه أيضاً تخرج للتو من جامعة من الجامعات القوية،
and that he worked at a very impressive Wall Street bank.
وأنه يعمل في بنك من البنوك الشهيرة في "وول ستريت".
But what made the biggest impression on me that first meeting
ولكن ما كان له الأثر الأكبر علي في هذا اللقاء الأول
was that he was smart and funny
أنه كان ذكياً ومضحكاً.
and he looked like a farm boy.
وكان يشبه أولاد المزارع
He had these big cheeks, these big apple cheeks
كانت لديه وجنتين كبيرتين ، الوجنات التي تشبه التفاح الكبير
and this wheat-blond hair,
والشعر الأشقر القمحي،
and he seemed so sweet.
وبدا أنه لطيف جداً.
One of the smartest things Conor did, from the very beginning,
من أكثر الأشياء الذكية التي فعلها "كونر" ، من البداية
was to create the illusion that I was the dominant partner in the relationship.
خلق هذا الوهم بأنني أنا الشريك المسيطر بالعلاقة.
He did this especially at the beginning
فعل هذا بالتحديد في البداية
by idolizing me.
بتأليهي.
We started dating, and he loved everything about me,
بدأنا بالمواعدة، وكان يحب كل شيء في،
that I was smart, that I'd gone to Harvard,
أنني كنت ذكية ، أنني ذهبت لهارفارد
that I was passionate about helping teenage girls, and my job.
أنني كنت أحب مساعدة الفتيات المراهقات، وعملي.
He wanted to know everything about my family
كان يريد أن يعرف كل شيئ عن عائلتي
and my childhood and my hopes and dreams.
عن طفولتي عن أمالي وأحلامي.
Conor believed in me, as a writer and a woman,
كونور آمن بي ، ككاتبة و كإمرأة،
in a way that no one else ever had.
بطريقة لم يفعلها أحد من قبل.
And he also created a magical atmosphere of trust between us
وهو أيضاُ خلق جو سحري من الثقة بيننا
by confessing his secret,
عن طريق اعترافه بسره،
which was that, as a very young boy starting at age four,
الذي كان أنه ،في عمر صغير جدا من بداية عمر الرابعة
he had been savagely and repeatedly physically abused
كان يتعرض بطريقة وحشية ومتكررة للاعتداء الجسدي
by his stepfather,
من زوج أمه،
and the abuse had gotten so bad that he had had to drop out of school in eighth grade,
والاعتداء وصل لمستوى سيئ إلى الدرجة التي تسبب في خروجه من المدرسة في الصف الثامن،
even though he was very smart,
مع أنه كان ذكياً جداً،
and he'd spent almost 20 years rebuilding his life.
وقد قضى حوالي العشرون سنة يعيد بناء حياته.
Which is why that Ivy League degree
لهاذا السبب شهادته من الجامعة القوية
and the Wall Street job and his bright shiny future
وعمله في "وول ستريت" ومستقبله المشرق المنير
meant so much to him.
كانوا يعنون له الشيء الكثير.
If you had told me
لو قلت لي في السابق
that this smart, funny, sensitive man who adored me
أن هذا الرجل الذكي ،المرح ، الحساس الذي عشقني
would one day dictate whether or not I wore makeup,
في يوم من الأيام سيتحكم ما إذا كنت أضع المكياج أم لا،
how short my skirts were,
ما مقدار قصر تنورتي،
where I lived, what jobs I took,
أين سكنت وأي وظيفة أخذت،
who my friends were and where I spent Christmas,
من هم أصحابي وأين قضيت أعياد الميلاد،
I would have laughed at you,
كنت لضحكت عليك.
because there was not a hint of violence or control
لأنه لم يكن هناك أي تلميح لعدوانية أو تحكم
or anger in Conor at the beginning.
أو غضب عند "كونر" في البداية.
I didn't know that the first stage
لم أكن أعلم أن أول مرحلة
in any domestic violence relationship
في أي علاقة عنف أسري
is to seduce and charm the victim.
هي أن تغري وتفتن الضحية.
I also didn't know that the second step is to isolate the victim.
ولم أكن أعلم أن ثاني خطوة هي أن تعزل الضحية.
Now, Conor did not come home one day and announce,
الأن ،"كونر" لم يأتي البيت في يوم وأعلن
"You know, hey, all this Romeo and Juliet stuff has been great,
"هل تعلمين، يا ، أن كل أمور روميو وجولييت كانت رائعة،
but I need to move into the next phase
لكن لابد أنتقل لمرحلة أخرى
where I isolate you and I abuse you" — (Laughter) —
حيث اعزلك وأعتدي عليك"-(ضحكة)-
"so I need to get you out of this apartment
"لذلك علي أن أخرجك من هذه الشقة
where the neighbors can hear you scream
اللتي يستطيع الجيران فيها أن يسمعونك تصرخين
and out of this city where you have friends and family
و خارج هذه المدينة التي لديك فيها أصحاب وأهل
and coworkers who can see the bruises."
وزملاء عمل الذين يمكن أن يروا الرضوض"
Instead, Conor came home one Friday evening
عوضاً عن ذلك، "كونر" رجع البيت في مساء يوم جمعة
and he told me that he had quit his job that day,
وقال لي أنه ترك عمله في ذلك اليوم،
his dream job,
وظيفة حلمه،
and he said that he had quit his job because of me,
وقال أنه ترك وظيفته من أجلي،
because I had made him feel so safe and loved
لأنني جعلته يشعر أنه في أمان ومحبوب
that he didn't need to prove himself on Wall Street anymore,
أنه لا يحتاج أن يثبت نفسه في "وول ستريت" بعد الآن،
and he just wanted to get out of the city
و هو ققط يريد أن يخرج من المدينة
and away from his abusive, dysfunctional family,
وبعيداً عن عائلته المعنِفة والمختلة،
and move to a tiny town in New England
وأن ينتقل الي مدينة صغيرة في "نيو انجلاند"
where he could start his life over with me by his side.
بحيث يبدأ حياته من جديد معي بجابنه.
Now, the last thing I wanted to do was leave New York,
الآن، آخر شيء كنت أريده هو أن أترك نيويورك،
and my dream job,
ووظيفة حلمي،
but I thought you made sacrifices for your soulmate,
ولكنني فكرت أنك تقدم تضحيات لتوأم روحك،
so I agreed, and I quit my job,
فوافقت، وتركت عملي،
and Conor and I left Manhattan together.
و "كونر" وأنا تركنا "مانهاتن" معا.
I had no idea I was falling into crazy love,
لم تكن لدي ادنى فكرة أنني أقع في حب مجنون،
that I was walking headfirst into a carefully laid
أنني أخطو برأسي نحو ما وضِع بدقة
physical, financial and psychological trap.
فخ جسدي ومالي ونفسي.
The next step in the domestic violence pattern
الخطوة الثانية في نمط العنف الأسري
is to introduce the threat of violence
هو تقديم تهديد العنف
and see how she reacts.
وترى كيف تتفاعل.
And here's where those guns come in.
وهنا تأتي تلك المسدسات.
As soon as we moved to New England -- you know,
حالما انتقلنا إلى"نيو انجلاند" -- تعرفون،
that place where Connor was supposed to feel so safe --
ذلك المكان الذي يفترض أن يحس فيه كونر بالأمان--
he bought three guns.
اشترى ثلاث مسدسات.
He kept one in the glove compartment of our car.
وضع واحد في درج السيارة.
He kept one under the pillows on our bed,
وضع واحد تحت مخدات سريرنا،
and the third one he kept in his pocket at all times.
والثالث حفظه في جيبه طوال الوقت.
And he said that he needed those guns
وقال أنه يحتاج هذه المسدسات
because of the trauma he'd experienced as a young boy.
بسبب الصدمة التي تعرض لها عندما كان فتىً صغيراً.
He needed them to feel protected.
احتاجهم ليشعر بالأمان.
But those guns were really a message for me,
ولكن تلك المسدسات كانوا بالحقيقة رسالة لي،
and even though he hadn't raised a hand to me,
وبالرغم من أنه لم يرفع يد علي،
my life was already in grave danger every minute of every day.
حياتي كانت قد أصبحت في خطر كبير في كل دقيقة من كل يوم.
Conor first physically attacked me
"كونر" أعتدى جسديا علي أولاً
five days before our wedding.
خمس أيام قبل زفافنا.
It was 7 a.m. I still had on my nightgown.
كانت الساعة السابعة صباحاً. وكنت لا ازال بملابس النوم.
I was working on my computer trying to finish a freelance writing assignment,
كنت أشتغل على جهازي الحاسوب أحاول انهاء مهمة مستقلة بالكتابة ،
and I got frustrated,
فأصبحت محبطة
and Conor used my anger as an excuse
و"كونر" استخدمت غضبي كعذر
to put both of his hands around my neck
ليضع يديه الاثنتين حول عنقي
and to squeeze so tightly that I could not breathe or scream,
ويضغط بشدة بحيث لم أستطع التنفس أو الصراخ،
and he used the chokehold
وأستخدم وضعية الخنق
to hit my head repeatedly against the wall.
ليضرب رأسي مراراً بالجدار.
Five days later, the ten bruises on my neck had just faded,
خمسة أيام بعدها، الرضوض العشر على عنقي تلاشت
and I put on my mother's wedding dress,
ولبست فستان زفاف والدتي،
and I married him.
وتزوجته.
Despite what had happened,
على الرغم مما حدث،
I was sure we were going to live happily ever after,
كنت متأكدة أننا سنعيش سعيدين للأبد،
because I loved him, and he loved me so much.
لأنني أحببته، وأحبني كثيراً.
And he was very, very sorry.
وكان متأسفاً جدا،جداً.
He had just been really stressed out by the wedding
كان فقط متوتراً جداً من الزفاف
and by becoming a family with me.
وبأن يكون عائلة معي.
It was an isolated incident,
كانت حادثة منعزلة،
and he was never going to hurt me again.
ولم يكن ليؤذيني مرة أخرى.
It happened twice more on the honeymoon.
حدثت مرتين أكثر في شهر العسل.
The first time, I was driving to find a secret beach
المرة الأولى، كنت أقود السيارة لأبحث عن شاطئ سري
and I got lost,
وضللت الطريق
and he punched me in the side of my head so hard
ولكمني على جانب رأسي بشدة
that the other side of my head repeatedly hit
لدرجة أن الجانب الآخر من رأسي ضرب بصورة متتالية
the driver's side window.
النافذة الجانبية لسائق السيارة.
And then a few days later, driving home from our honeymoon,
وبعدها بأيام معدودة، في طريق العودة من شهر العسل،
he got frustrated by traffic,
استشاط غضباً من زحمة المرور
and he threw a cold Big Mac in my face.
ورمى برجر"بيج ماك" على وجهي.
Conor proceeded to beat me once or twice a week
"كونر" استمر في ضربي مرة أو مرتين اسبوعيا
for the next two and a half years of our marriage.
خلال السنتين والنصف التاليتين من زواجنا.
I was mistaken in thinking that I was unique
كنت مخطئة في تفكيري أنني فريدة
and alone in this situation.
ووحيدة في هذا الوضع.
One in three American women
واحدة من كل ثلاث نساء أمريكيات
experiences domestic violence or stalking at some point in her life,
تمر بتجربة العنف الأسري أو المطاردة في فترة من حياتها.
and the CDC reports that 15 million children
وال "سي دي سي" يعلن أن 15 مليون طفل
are abused every year, 15 million.
يتعرض للاعتداء كل سنة، 15 مليون.
So actually, I was in very good company.
لذا حقاً، كنت مع صحبة جيدة.
Back to my question:
عودةً إلى سؤالي:
Why did I stay?
لماذا بقيت؟
The answer is easy.
الجواب سهل.
I didn't know he was abusing me.
لم أكن أعرف أنه يسيء إلي.
Even though he held those loaded guns to my head,
على الرغم من أنه صوب تلك المسدسات المحشوة على رأسي.
pushed me down stairs,
دفعني إلى أسفل السلالم.
threatened to kill our dog,
هدد بقتل كلبنا،
pulled the key out of the car ignition as I drove down the highway,
سحب المفتاح من مشعل السيارة خلال قيادتي بالطريق السريع،
poured coffee grinds on my head
صب البن المطحون على رأسي
as I dressed for a job interview,
وأنا مرتدية ملابسي لاجراء مقابلة عمل،
I never once thought of myself as a battered wife.
لم أفكر أبداً بأنني زوجة معنفَة.
Instead, I was a very strong woman
على العكس، كنت امرأة قوية
in love with a deeply troubled man,
في حالة حب مع شخص مضطرب جداً.
and I was the only person on Earth
وكنت الوحيدة على وجه الأرض
who could help Conor face his demons.
القادرة على مساعدة "كونر" في مواجهة شياطينه.
The other question everybody asks is,
السؤال الآخر الذي يسأله الجميع
why doesn't she just leave?
لماذا فقط لا ترحل ؟
Why didn't I walk out? I could have left any time.
لماذا لم أخرج ؟ كنت أستطيع المغادرة في أي وقت
To me, this is the saddest and most painful question that people ask,
بالنسبة لي، هذا هو أكثر سؤال محزن ومؤلم يسأله الناس،
because we victims know something you usually don't:
لأننا نحن الضحايا نعرف شيئاً لا تعرفونه أنتم:
It's incredibly dangerous to leave an abuser.
من الخطورة الشديدة أن تترك المعتدي.
Because the final step in the domestic violence pattern
لأن الخطوة الأخيرة في نمط العنف الأسري
is kill her.
هي اقتلها.
Over 70 percent of domestic violence murders
أكثر من 70% من حالات القتل في العنف الأسري
happen after the victim has ended the relationship,
تحدث بعد أن تنهي الضحية العلاقة،
after she's gotten out,
بعد أن تكون قد خرجت
because then the abuser has nothing left to lose.
لأن لم يعد هناك للمعتدي شيء ليخسره.
Other outcomes include long-term stalking,
نتائج أخرى تتضمن مطاردة طويلة المدى.
even after the abuser remarries;
حتى إذا تزوج المعتدي مرة أخرى،
denial of financial resources;
انكار مصادر مالية،
and manipulation of the family court system
وتلاعب في نظام المحاكم الأسرية
to terrify the victim and her children,
لارهاب الضحية وأطفالها،
who are regularly forced by family court judges
الذين وبصورة منتظمة يجبرون من قضاة المحاكم الأسرية
to spend unsupervised time
على قضاء وقت غير مراقب
with the man who beat their mother.
مع الشخص الذي يضرب أمهم.
And still we ask, why doesn't she just leave?
ونبقى نسأل: لماذا فقط لا ترحل؟
I was able to leave,
كنت قادرة على الرحيل
because of one final, sadistic beating
بسبب ضربة اخيرة سادية
that broke through my denial.
كسرت حالة انكاري.
I realized that the man who I loved so much
أدركت أن الرجل الذي أحببته كثيراً
was going to kill me if I let him.
كان سيقتلني لو سمحت له.
So I broke the silence.
فكسرت الصمت.
I told everyone:
وقلت للجميع
the police, my neighbors,
الشرطة، جيراني
my friends and family, total strangers,
أصحابي وأهلي وأشخاص غرباء تماماً
and I'm here today because you all helped me.
وأنا هنا لأنكم جميعاً ساعدتموني.
We tend to stereotype victims
نحن نميل لوضع صورة نمطية للضحايا
as grisly headlines,
كعناوين مروعة
self-destructive women, damaged goods.
نساء مدمرين أنفسهم، بضائع تالفة
The question, "Why does she stay?"
السؤال، " لما تبقى؟"
is code for some people for, "It's her fault for staying,"
اشارة من بعض الناس على " أنه ما يحدث لها خطئها لأنها بقت"
as if victims intentionally choose to fall in love with men
كأن الضحايا يتعمدون اختيار الوقوع في حب رجال
intent upon destroying us.
ينوون على تدميرنا.
But since publishing "Crazy Love,"
لكن من وقت نشر " حب مجنون"
I have heard hundreds of stories from men and women
سمعت الكثير من القصص من رجال ونساء
who also got out,
ممن أيضاً خرجوا
who learned an invaluable life lesson from what happened,
ممن تعلموا درس حياة لايقدر بثمن من ما حصل
and who rebuilt lives -- joyous, happy lives --
وممن قاموا باعادة بناء حياة --مبهجة، حياة سعيدة--
as employees, wives and mothers,
كموظفين ، زوجات وأمهات،
lives completely free of violence, like me.
حياة خالية من العنف، مثلي أنا.
Because it turns out that I'm actually a very typical domestic violence victim
لأنه تبين أنني ضحية نمطية جدا للعنف الأسري
and a typical domestic violence survivor.
وناجية نمطية من العنف الأسري.
I remarried a kind and gentle man,
تزوجت مرة أخرى بـرجل طيب ولطيف،
and we have those three kids.
ولدينا هؤلاء الأطفال الثلاثة.
I have that black lab, and I have that minivan.
لدي ذلك الكلب اللابوردي الأسود ولدي تلك الحافلة الصغيرة.
What I will never have again,
الشيء الذي لن يكون لدي مرة أخرى
ever,
أبداً،
is a loaded gun held to my head
هو مسدس محشو مصوب عند رأسي
by someone who says that he loves me.
من شخص يقول أنه يحبني.
Right now, maybe you're thinking,
في هذه الأثناء، قد تفكرون
"Wow, this is fascinating,"
"رائع، هذا شيء جميل،"
or, "Wow, how stupid was she,"
أو "رائع، كم كانت غبية،"
but this whole time, I've actually been talking about you.
ولكن طوال هذا الوقت، كنت في الواقع أتكلم عنكم.
I promise you there are several people
اؤكد لكم ان هناك عدة أشخاص
listening to me right now
من الذين يسمعونني الآن
who are currently being abused
يتعرضون حالياً للعنف
or who were abused as children
أو تعرضوا للعنف وهم أطفال
or who are abusers themselves.
أو هم أنفسهم معتدون.
Abuse could be affecting your daughter,
اعتداء قد يكون مؤثراً في ابنتك،
your sister, your best friend right now.
أختك، صديقتك المفضلة الآن.
I was able to end my own crazy love story
كنت قادرة على انهاء قصة الحب المجنون الخاصة بي
by breaking the silence.
عن طريق كسر الصمت.
I'm still breaking the silence today.
أنا لازلت أكسر الصمت اليوم.
It's my way of helping other victims,
هي طريقتي في مساعدة ضحايا آخرين،
and it's my final request of you.
وهو أخر طلب مني لكم.
Talk about what you heard here.
تكلموا عن ما سمعتموه هنا.
Abuse thrives only in silence.
العنف يزدهر فقط في السكوت.
You have the power to end domestic violence
لديك القدرة على انهاء العنف الأسري
simply by shining a spotlight on it.
ببساطة عن طريق تسليط الضوء عليه.
We victims need everyone.
نحن الضحايا نحتاج للجميع.
We need every one of you to understand
نحتاجكم جميعاً أن تفهموا
the secrets of domestic violence.
أسرار العنف الأسري.
Show abuse the light of day by talking about it
أظهروا العنف للنور بكلامكم عنه
with your children, your coworkers,
مع أطفالكم، مع زملائكم بالعمل،
your friends and family.
أصدقائكم والعائلة
Recast survivors as wonderful, lovable people
صوروا الناجيين على أنهم أناس رائعين ومحبوبين
with full futures.
بمستقبل كامل.
Recognize the early signs of violence
تعرفوا على العلامات المبكرة من العنف
and conscientiously intervene,
وتدخلوا بضمير
deescalate it, show victims a safe way out.
خففوه، أروا الضحايا طريق آمن للخروج.
Together we can make our beds,
سوياً نستطيع جعل أَسِرتنا ،
our dinner tables and our families
طاولات عشائنا وعائلاتنا
the safe and peaceful oases they should be.
واحات آمنة وهادئة مثل ما يجب أن تكون.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)